Evil takes many forms.
The Witch is a horror, fantasy, drama film directed by Robert Eggers.
In 1630, a farmer relocates his family to a remote plot of land on the
edge of a forest where strange, unsettling things happen.
With suspicion and paranoia mounting, each family member's
faith, loyalty and love are tested in shocking ways.
Thomasin, played by Anya Taylor-Joy.
William, played by Ralph Ineson.
Katherine, played by Kate Dickie.
Caleb, played by Harvey Scrimshaw.
Mercy, played by Ellie Grainger.
Jonas, played by Lucas Dawson.
The Witch (stylized as The VVitch, and subtitled A New-England Folktale) is a 2015 folk horror
film written and directed by Robert Eggers in his feature directorial debut.
It stars Anya Taylor-Joy in her feature film debut, alongside Ralph Ineson,
Kate Dickie, Harvey Scrimshaw, Ellie Grainger, and Lucas Dawson.
Set in 1630s New England, the narrative follows a Puritan family who are
preyed upon by an evil force in the woods beyond their farm.
In fear and desperation, they turn upon one another even when the
oldest daughter is suspected of being a witch.
An international co-production of the United States and Canada, the film premiered at the Sundance
Film Festival on January 27, 2015, and was widely released by A24 on February 19, 2016.
It was a critical and financial success, grossing $40 million against a $4 million budget, and is
considered by some to be one of the best horror films of the 2010s and the 21st century.
The film explores themes of witch, isolation, magic, possession, black magic.
The tone is dark and emotional.